Guide to the David Finn papers, 1978-1990 and undated RL.11727
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
David Finn papers
1978-1990 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Finn, David, 1921-
RL.11727
0.2 Linear Feet
Business executive, photographer and author based in New York; considered a pioneer in the field of public relations. David Finn papers include memos, art exhibit brochures, Ruder Finn print advertising and publications, and articles written by Finn and others. Companies represented include American Can, General Mills, Ruder & Finn, and Whirlpool. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Business executive, photographer and author based in New York; considered a pioneer in the field of public relations. Born 1921; graduated City College of New York; co-founded Ruder & Finn 1948 with William Ruder; remaned Ruder-Finn 1989; 2006 winner of John W. Hill Award; PR Week Hall of Fame 2015
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The David Finn papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2007.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Cause Marketing Forum. Halo Awards records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Evan Peters scrapbooks
J. Walter Thompson Company. Jack Hilton papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Loy Baxter papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Public Relations records
John R. Blaney papers
Outdoor Advertising Association of America archives
Collection Overview
David Finn papers include memos, art exhibit brochures, Ruder Finn print advertising and publications, and articles written by Finn and others. Companies represented include American Can, General Mills, Ruder & Finn, and Whirlpool. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising agencies; Advertising executives; Public relations; Arts -- Publicity; Authors, American; Photographers; Ruder & Finn; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; American Can Company; General Mills, Inc
- David Finn Papers, 1978-1990 and undated; 1
  - A Must for Effective Corporate Philanthropy: Good Communications (Betty Cott), undated (Box 1)
  - America's Threatened Third Sector (John D. Rockefeller 3rd), 1978 (Box 1)
  - American Can Company--America Can! program brochure, 1984 (Box 1)
  - CEO: The Whole Man--Do Oil and Art Mix (interview with Rawleigh Warner Jr.), 1985 (Box 1)
  - General Mills American Family Report: Family Health in an Era of Stress, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Henry Moore exhibit (photographs by David Finn), 1983 (Box 1)
  - High-Tech Women at the Top (interview with Marisa Bellisario), 1988 (Box 1)
  - How to Communicate an Idea (David Finn, Ruder Finn The Forum), 1986 (Box 1)
  - Media Awards for Economic Understanding, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Memos from David Finn, undated (Box 1)
  - Public Invisibility of Corporate Leaders (David Finn, Harvard Business Review), 1980 (Box 1)
  - Ruder Finn & Rothman brochure, undated (Box 1)
  - Ruder Finn house ad "Independent", undated (Box 1)
  - Ruder Finn name change announcement, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Speaking Out in Public: A Consultant's View (William Ruder), 1979 (Box 1)
  - The Real Cellini--Photographs by David Finn exhibit brochure, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Thoughts and Images (David Finn, Public Relations Journal), 1984 (Box 1)
  - University of Wyoming gift agreement, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Walking Tours of America: Paterson, Hamilton's Dream (Mark Stuart), 1978 (Box 1)
  - Whirlpool Report on Consumers in the 80s: America's Search for Equality, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Who Needs Poetry (David Finn, Harvard Business Review), 1989 (Box 1)
  - Working in the Twenty-First Century symposium, 1979 (Box 1)